Benjamin Tallmadge Collection
Litchfield Historical Society
- Miscellany, 1783-1834
  - Memo, 1800 (Folder 6)
    Concerning Benjamin Tallmadge's share in the Ohio Company.
  - Eulogy, 1805 (Folder 7)
    For Mary (Hallett) Tallmadge.
  - Poetry by Benjamin Tallmadge, 1808 (Folder 8)
    Contains "The Sick Saint's Meditation," with reference to Mrs. Hallett; and "A Hymn."
  - Church seating plan (oversize), 1813 (Folder 9)
    Seating chart of Litchfield Meeting-House. See largest oversize box.
  - Certificates, 1811, 1816 (Folder 10)
    John Paine Cushman's certificate to practice as attorney, and as solicitor in the Court of Chancery in New York.
  - Poetry by Benjamin Tallmadge, 1809-1822 (Folder 11)
    Contains "An Ode Written on New Years Morning"; Reflections for the 25th of Feby. 1811," on his sixtieth birthday; and "Lines Written Subsequent to the Funeral of Miss Helen Peck."
  - Circular, 1822 (Folder 12)
    Printed circular addressed to former students of Tapping Reeve, asking for donations.
  - Certificates (oversize), 1807-1825 (Folder 13)
    Contains Benjamin Tallmadge's naval commission signed by James Monroe; and John Paine Cushman's Yale University diploma and certificate to practice as counsellor in New York. See oversize box.
  - Revolutionary claims, 1828 (Folder 14)
    Printed letter, with Benjamin Tallmadge's reply, concerning an act for the relief of surviving officers and soldiers of the army of the Revolutionary War.
  - Lines written on the death..., 1831 (Folder 15)
    Anonymous poem on the death of Lieut. Benjamin Tallmadge, Jr.
  - Marche des Marseillois, n. d. (Folder 16)
    Anonymous poem.
- Frederick A. Tallmadge papers, 1811-1864
  Series 5 consists of the papers of Benjamin Tallmadge's son, Frederick Augustus Tallmadge. Many of the letters concern Frederick Tallmadge's publication of his father's memoirs. Others record, and express appreciation for, Tallmadge's public service in New York and in Congress.
  The first subseries, Tallmadge's correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The second subseries, Tallmadge's miscellaneous papers, are arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence, 1840-1864
    - Baldwin, Robert, 1854, 1861 (Folder 1)
    - Bancroft, George, 1859 (Folder 2)
    - Beebe, W. R. et. al., 1853 (Folder 3)
    - Beers (?), S. P., 1859 (Folder 4)
    - Boardman, D. S., 1859 (Folder 5)
    - Boynton, E., 1862 (Folder 6)
    - Briggs, George, 1848 (Folder 7)
    - Crisfield, J., 1863 (Folder 8)
    - Crowninshield, Francis, 1848 (Folder 9)
    - Everett, Edward, 1848 (Folder 10)
    - Fillmore, Millard, et. al., 1840 (Folder 11)
    - Gould, William, 1859 (Folder 12)
    - Kilbourne, P. K., 1859 (Folder 13)
    - Lossing, Benson, 1859 (Folder 14)
    - New York State Library, 1859 (Folder 15)
    - Prall, W. et. al., 1846 (Folder 16)
    - Quincy, Josiah, 1859 (Folder 17)
    - Silliman, Benjamin, 1864 (Folder 18)
    - Smith, Truman, 1859 (Folder 19)
    - Stuyvesant, Peter, 1841 (Folder 20)
    - Suydam, Lambert, 1840 (Folder 21)
    - Thistlecoss (?), Robert, 1848, 1859 (Folder 22)
  - Miscellany, 1811-1853
    - Diploma, 1811 (Folder 1)
    - Passport, 1816 (Folder 2)
    - Certificate, 1848 (Folder 3)
      Admitting F. A. Tallmadge to attorney and counselor of the United States Supreme Court.
    - U. S. Congress committee, 1848 (Folder 4)
      Formation of committee to escort John Quincy Adams' remains to its place of interment.
    - List of subscribers, 1853 (Folder 5)
      List of subscribers for a set of plate to be presented to F. A. Tallmadge as Recorder of New York City.
    - Speech, n. d. (Folder 6)
      Speech concerning the interment of John Quincy Adams' remains.
    - Smith, John Cotton, 1812 Jul 27 (Folder 7)
      Letter from Hartford to Hon. Judson Canfield requesting that a meeting of the Council of State be held in the absence of the governor. Frederick A. Tallmadge married Eliza Canfield, daughter of Judson Canfield of Sharon, Conn.